Guide to the Yale Divinity School STM Theses
Yale University Divinity School Library
Yale Divinity School STM Theses
1929-1995
RG 41
Yale University Divinity School Library
20
(49 boxes)
The theses in Series I (1975-1982) and those available in microfiche format in Series IV (1975-1995) were submitted for the S.T.M. degree at Yale Divinity School. The theses in Series II (1939-1956) were submitted to YDS during an earlier era. Series III contains a miscellaneous collection of theses that have some Yale connection. The theses in this collection are mostly from Yale Divinity School, but some theses related to Yale or its collections are also included.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Over the years there have been varying practices regarding the deposit of YDS theses in the Divinity Library. This collection is not comprehensive of all YDS theses ever submitted for degrees, but rather merely represents the ones that have been deposited in the library.
Scope and Contents
I. S.T.M. Theses, 1975-1982
II. Earlier YDS Theses, 1939-1956
III. Other Theses
IV. S.T.M. Theses on Microfiche, 1975-1995
The theses in Series I were submitted as partial fulfillment of the requirements for the S.T.M. degree at Yale Divinity School. This is not a comprehensive collection of all S.T.M. theses submitted to YDS. Selected papers were nominated for deposit in the Divinity School Library each year. The theses in Series II are those submitted to YDS during an earlier era, while those in Series III are a miscellaneous collection of theses with some Yale connection.
The papers are grouped by the year in which they were submitted and are arranged alphabetically by author within each year.
Arrangement
I. S.T.M. Theses, 1975-1982
II. Earlier YDS Theses, 1939-1956
III. Other Theses
IV. S.T.M. Theses on Microfiche, 1975-1995
- S.T.M. Theses, 1975-1985, Series I
  - Cockburn, Michael: The Mission of the Church in the Development of a South Caribbean People. Advisors: Kyaw Than, Charles Forman, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Conner, Gerald W.: Perspectives of Pastoral Ministry. Advisors: Edward F. Dobihal, Jr., James Clague, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Flower, Edward E., Jr.: The Significance of Divine Presence in Pastoral Care. Advisors: Edward F. Dobihal, Jr., James G. Clague, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Kuck, David W.: The Use and Canonization of Acts in the Early Church. Advisors: Rowan Greer, Abraham Malherbe, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Nehring, David: A Dependable Ministry: a pilot study of some effects of the Tavistock model of group relations training on selected British clergy and religious institutions. Advisors: Edward F. Dobihal, Jr., Michael Allen, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Evans, Linda Mary: An Exploration into the Nature of Suffering Through a Study of Persons. Advisor: Edward F. Dobihal, Jr., 1976 (Box 2)
  - Rhorer, Thomas L.: Preserving the Earth: Approaches to Man's Relationship with Other Creatures. Advisors: David H. Kelsey, Gene Outka, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Schulze, Thomas Robert: Anointing of the Sick: Some Traditions and Symbolisms of Christian Healing. Advisors: Aidan Kavanaugh, Henri J. M. Nouwen, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Mathew, Thomson K.: Pastoral Care Problems Unique to Pentecostal Congregations. Advisors:Francis X. Cheney, Barbara Hargrove, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Morris, Donald Dean: The Doctrine of Divine Efficiency in the Theology of Nathanael Emmons. Advisors: Sydney E. Ahlstrom, Colin W. Williams, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Oostrom, Alexander Quirinus Maria: Guilt and Forgiveness. Advisors: Henri Nouwen, Robert Anderson, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Colon, Ruben Dario: C.S. Lewis and Becoming a Thoughtful Person. Advisors: Paul L. Holmer, Randolph C. Miller, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Gneuhs, Geoffrey B.: Peter Maurin: The Life and Thought of the Founder of the Catholic Worker Movement. Advisors: George Lindbeck, Margaret Farley, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Harbour, William D.: The Ministry of Sustaining in the Pastoral Care of a Particular Group of the Sick: Hospitalized Open Heart Surgery Patients and Cancer Patients. Advisors: Eward J. Dobihal, Jr., Luke T. Johnson, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Jensen, Janice C.: Confirmation: The Birth of a Lutheran Christian (One Stream from Luther to the Service Book and Hymnal). Advisors: Aidan Kavanaugh, George Lindbeck, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Lawther, Richard C.: Meditations on the Church and the Power. Advisors: Paul L. Holmer, Colin W. Williams, 1978 (Box 4)
  - McClester, John. A Liturgical History of Battell Chapel 1930-1975. Advisors: Jeffery Rowthorn, E. William Muehl, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Dunham, Robert E.: The Self and Its Potential: Theological Considerations. Advisors: David H. Kelsey, Gene Outka, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Lin, Paul Sunbeng: Paul's Conversion and His Mission. Advisors: Nils A. Dahl, Carl Holladay, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Quarm, Samuel E. A.: Pastoral Care in Relation to Polygamy Versus Monogamy in Ghana: A Study in Pastoral Care and African Christianity. Advisors: Harry Adams, David Allen, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Wardlaw, Theodore J.: H. Richard Niebuhr's Thought on the Church: A Genetic Study. Advisors: Sydney E. Ahlstrom, Rowan A. Greer, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Brown, Leroy: Ministry of the Black Church to the Black Family. Advisors: Charles Brown, Leon Watts., 1980 (Box 6)
  - Coho, Frank E.: The Augsburg-Confession Hymn of Nicolaus Ludwig, Count von Zinzendorf. Advisors: George Lindbeck, Jeffrey Rowthorn, 1981 (Box 6.5)
  - Fete, Josept N.: The Cultural Background of the Roman Ritual of Baptism. Advisors: Aidan Kavanagh, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Norwood, M. Thomas, Jr.: Cherishing the Word: The Canon and the Community of Faith. Advisors: Brevard Childs, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Nunez, Joseph Armando: The Privilege of the Poor. Advisors: Letty Russell, 1981 (Box 6.5)
  - Thornhill, Cleveland S., II: The role of the Contemporary Christian Church in Health Care: A Case Study. Advisors: Edward Dobihal, Jr., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Campbell, Charles: Christians and the American Political Process: A Study of the Relationship Between Christianity and Politics in the Thought of John Courtney Murray, John Howard Yoder, and John C. Bennett. Advisors: Margaret Farley, William Muehl, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Choi, Jai-Keun: A Historical Study of the Shinto Shrine Worship in the Korean Church. Advisors: Charles Forman, John Stroup, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Ebenezer, Catherine: Sex Roles, Evolution and Ethics: A Critique of Alice Rossi's "A Biosocial Perspective on Parenting". Advisors: Margaret Farley, Letty Russell, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Hawkins, William L: Infant Baptism in the Thought of John Calvin and Karl Barth: A Problem in Reformed Theology, 1982 (Box 6.5)
  - Moody, Charles C.: Tertullian, Cyprian and Martyr-Theology in Third Centure Carthage. Advisors: Rowan Greer, George Lindbeck, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Roffey, John W.: Wisdom, Law and Blessing: An Ethical Hermeneutic of Deuteronomy and Matthew. Advisors: Brevard Childs, Robert Wilson, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Seitz, Christopher R.: The Place of the Servant Songs in Second Isaiah. Advisors: Robert Wilson, Lansing Hicks, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Sevaaetasi, Leanavaotana Sekuini: A Study of the Cultural and Indigenous Religious Beliefs, and Their Help and Influence in the Understanding, and the Accepting of Christianity in Samoa. Advisors: Letty Russell, Charles Forman, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Simmons, Michael Bland: A Study of Graeco-Roman Pagan and Christian Soteriologies of the Second Century A.D. Advisors: Rowan Greer, John Stroup, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Kim, Bock-Ja: Autonomy of Language in L. Wittgenstein, n.d. (Box 6.5)
  - Choi, Doug Sung: The Conflicts on the Views of the Bible in the Presbyterian Church of Korea, 1985 (Box 8)
- S.T.M. Theses, 1939-1966, Series II
  - Akagi, Tai: Why Christian Education? - Prolegomena. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 1A)
  - Arnold, John William: Pioneer Protestant Educational Missions to China, 1807-1857. (2 copies), 1948 (Box 1A)
  - Ashley, Albert R.: The Southern Methodist Church. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 2A)
  - Ayers, Stephen: A Study of the Commission on Evangelism and Devotional Life of the Congregational Denomination in America. (2 copies), 1940 (Box 2A)
  - Ball, George Hudson: Some Behavior Traits of American Soldiers in the Forces of Occupation with Special Reference to Ethical and Cultural Norms. (2 copies), 1946 (Box 3A)
  - Barnes, Paul E.: Christian Conversion: The Meaning and Relevance of Conversion in the Light of New Testament Thought. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 3A)
  - Beamesderfer, Sam H.: William Temple's Idea of God. (2 copies), 1948 (Box 4A)
  - Benson, W.E.: The Christian Life Course of the United Lutheran Church of America: An Evaluation. (1 copy), 1941 (Box 4A)
  - Bock, Paul: Ecumenical Reconstruction in Europe. (2 copies), 1951 (Box 4A)
  - Boehmke, A. Karl: Visitation Evangelism in the American Churches. (2 copies), 1954 (Box 5A)
  - Bollman, Oscar P.: The Foreign Mission School of Cornwall, Connecticut. (ABCFM) (2 copies), 1939 (Box 5A)
  - Bruking, Renate: Die Schupfungsvorstellung in Prov. 8, 22-31 (1 copy), 1966 (Box 40C)
  - Brown, Ray Bryan: The Form of the Church in the New Testament. (2 copies), 1948 (Box 6A)
  - Bull, Robert Jehu: Arnobius of Sicca, Christian Apologist. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 6A)
  - Burkle, Howard R.: Austin Farrer's View of Revelation and Reason. (2 copies), 1949 (Box 6A)
  - Campbell, Wilbur Fred: Dwight L. Moody and Religious Education. (2 copies), 1949 (Box 7A)
  - Carlson, Robert L.: A Critique of Richard Hooker's Law of Ecclesiastical Polity. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 7A)
  - Cartwright, Colbert Scott: The Life of Joseph Bellamy, 1719-1790. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 8A)
  - Clowney, Edmund P., Jr.: The Doctrine of the Self in the Philosophical Works of Soren Kierkegaard (2 copies), 1944 (Box 8A)
  - Cox, Alva I., Jr.: The Methodist Contribution to the Ecumenical Discussion of the Nature of the Church, the Ministry and Sacraments (1 copy), 1956 (Box 9A)
  - Durden, Lewis Minyon: The Army Character Guidance Program (2 copies), 1952 (Box 9A)
  - Esbjornson, Robert G.: Luther W. Youngdahl: A Christian in Politics (2 copies), 1954 (Box 10A)
  - Evans, Roy Morgan: American Colonization Society (2 copies), 1947 (Box 10A)
  - Farrar, James A.: Youth in the Church: A Manual on the Organization and Program of Youth Work for Adult Leaders of Youth in the Disciples of Christ Churches (2 copies), 1949 (Box 11A)
  - Finkenbine, Russell C.: Luther and Henry VIII (2 copies), 1946 (Box 11A)
  - Fraser, William P.: Authority in the Theology of John Wesley (2 copies), 1951 (Box 11A)
  - Gustafson, Henry A., Jr.: Paul's Conception of the Atonement and Its Relevance to Modern Preaching" (2 copies), 1952 (Box 12A)
  - Hall, (William McLaurine?): Organization of the Northern Baptist Convention (2 copies), 1955(?) (Box 12A)
  - Harada, David J.: Toward A Theology of the Mission of the Church (1 copy), 1956 (Box 13A)
  - Harris, Carl Y.: Origen: On Prayer (2 copies), 1947 (Box 13A)
  - Hawthorne, Robert J.: Doctrines of the Incarnation and Views of Man, in Three Thinkers: Irenaeus, William E. Channing, and Emil Brunner (2 copies), 1952 (Box 14A)
  - Hilgeman, Theophilus F. H.: The Life of Philip Schaff (2 copies), 1946 (Box 14A)
  - Horricks, J. T.: The Doctrine of Christian Nurture in the Heritage of the United Church of Canada (2 copies), 1948 (Box 15A)
  - Hostetter, Mark James: Pastoral Counseling (2 copies), 1940 (Box 15A)
  - Hudson, R. L.: A Burden for Souls: The Story of Sister Aimee and the Foursquare Gospel (2 copies), 1950 (Box 16A)
  - Imler, William A.: The Evangelistic Campaigns of Shehrwood Eddy in India and China: 1896-1931 (2 copies), 1953 (Box 16A)
  - Johnson, Alvin D.: A Study of the Place of Religion in Wesleyan University: 1831-1948, or Wesleyan's Religious Tradition (2 copies) (Box 16A)
  - Jones, Robert D.: America and Preaching During the Depression Years: 1930-1934 (2 copies), 1946 (Box 17A)
  - Keucher, Werner Gerald: The Decisions in the McCollum Case: People of the State of Illinois, ex rel. Vashti McCollum vs. Board of Education School District No. 71, Champaign County, Illinois, et. al., (No. 90, October Term, 1947, 333 U.S. 203) (2 copies), 1949 (Box 17A)
  - Kidder, Maurice Arthur: On the Teaching of Religion to Undergraduates (2 copies), 1946(?) (Box 17A)
  - Kildegaard, Axel C., Jr.: N.F.S. Grundtvie's Concept of Church and Community (2 copies), 1947 (Box 18A)
  - Kitney, Harold R.: An Introduction to the Study of Church Music and Worship (2 copies), 1953 (Box 18A)
  - Krapt, Gustav-Adolf: Karl Barth's Criticism of Friedrich Schleiermacher: An Evaluation (2 copies), 1950 (Box 18A)
  - Lawson, Harold B.: Speech Personality in Relation to the Army Chaplain (2 copies), 1952 (Box 19A)
  - Long, John D.: An Inquiry into the Concept of the Church as Revealed in the Lyman Beecher Lectures (2 copies), 1945 (Box 19A)
  - McManus, Harold Lynn: The Russian Church From the Conversion of Vladimir to the Bolshevik Revolution, (989-1917) (2 copies), 1948 (Box 19A)
  - Marx, Werner G.: Training Christian Workers Among a People of Low Cultural Level (2 copies), 1943 (Box 20A)
  - Mattingly, L. Edward: A Social Message for a Preaching Mission (2 copies), 1940 (Box 20A)
  - Meuser, Fred W.: Luther's Teaching on Baptism (2 copies), 1949 (Box 21A)
  - Moss, John A.: Representative Views of Man in Relation to Political Theory (1 copy), 1954 (Box 21A)
  - Myers, Howard William: The Ends of Government in Some Representative Christian Thinkers (2 copies), 1949 (Box 21A)
  - Neuser, Wilhelm: Das Gesetz in der Theologie Philip Melanchthons (2 copies), 1951 (Box 22A)
  - Ogasawara, Masatoshi: Luther's Iosa of the Church (2 copies), 1953 (Box 22A)
  - Oniki, Shozi Garry: Interracial Churches in American Protestantism (2 copies), 1951 (Box 22A)
  - Oosthuysen, Jacobus C.: The Dutch Reformed Churches and Inter-Group Relations in the Union of South Africa with Special Reference to the Period 1948-1958 (1 copy) (Box 23A)
  - Osborne, Byron Lindley, Jr.: The Person and Work of Jesus Christ in the Writings of John Wesley (2 copies), 1951 (Box 23A)
  - Post, Avery D.: The Preaching of Charles Reynolds Brown (2 copies), 1952 (Box 24A)
  - Rahn, Robert William: Schweitzer's Missionary Motivation (2 copies), 1952 (Box 24A)
  - Richards, Earnest D.: Anglican Views and Movements Towards Church Unity (2 copies), 1947 (Box 24A)
  - Richards, Egbert W.: Birth Control Legislation in Connecticut: A Study in the Conflict of Divergent Religious Views (2 copies), 1949 (Box 25A)
  - Sakata, Suteichi: On Charles Harold Dobb's Realized Eschatology (2 copies), 1941 (Box 25A)
  - Sengel, William R.: A Study of the Northern Urban Negro Church in the United States (2 copies), 1950 (Box 26A)
  - Shriver, Donald W., Jr.: Church Membership Requirements in Seventeenth Century New England Puritanism (1 copy), 1956 (Box 26A)
  - Sie, Ping-teh: Inquiry into the Religious Value of Mohism (2 copies), 1952 (Box 26A)
  - Smith, John Howard: William Allen Harper, Christian Educator (2 copies), 1949 (Box 27A)
  - Sonnack, Iver A.: The Development of Protestant Higher Education in China (2 copies), 1951 (Box 27A)
  - Spilman, Kenneth E.: The Small Church and the State College (2 copies), 1954 (Box 28A)
  - Strain, Dudley: The Prophets (2 copies), 1939 (Box 28A)
  - Tivade, David J.: The Social Gospel and the Social Order (2 copies), 1953 (Box 29A)
  - Torrence, Edgar C.: Informal Adult Education in the Young Men's Christian Associations of the United States (2 copies), 1950 (Box 29A)
  - Trick, J. Gordon: Religious Liberty in the Thought of Francis Wayland (1796-1865) (2 copies), 1946 (Box 29A)
  - Weinland, David E.: The Formulation and Specific Application of a Christian Philosophy of Higher Education (2 copies), 1949 (Box 30A)
  - West, William Garrett: The History of the East Association and Consociation of New Haven County with Special Reference to Ecclesiastical Courts 1786-1838 (2 copies), 1944 (Box 30A)
  - Westerberg, Wesley Magnus: Gustaf Aulen and the New Lutherforschung in Contemporary Swedish Theology (2 copies), 1945 (Box 31A)
  - Zuck, Lowell H.: The Zurich Anabaptists and the Rebirth of Christendom (2 copies), 1951 (Box 31A)
- Other Theses, Series III
  - Beach, Waldo: The Meaning and Authority of Conscience in Protestant Thought of Seventeenth Century England (Yale Ph.D.) (1 copy), 1944 (Box 32B)
  - Dawson, Dana, Jr.: A History of the Development of the Pacificist Movement in the Methodist Episcopal Church 1917-1932 (YDS Seminar) (1 copy), 1942 (Box 32B)
  - Eminhizer, Earl E.: The Rise and Fall of the Triennial Convention (M.Th. Thesis, Crozer Theological Seminary, Chester, PA) (1 copy), 1956 (Box 32B)
  - Hamrick, Randall Bender: An Evaluation of Contemporary Anglo-Catholic Ethics as Interpreted by Alfred E. Taylor and Kenneth Kirk (Yale Ph.D.) (1 copy), 1939 (Box 33B)
  - Rugh, Dwight D.: A Study of the Foreign Missionary Enterprise in the Life of the Student Christian Movement in the United States from 1806-1929 (Yale M.A.) (2 copies) (Box 33B)
  - Wiley, Edward Emerson, Jr.: Religion in Colonial Georgia (Yale M.A.) (1 copy), 1936 (Box 34B)
- S.T.M. Theses on Microfiche, Series IV
  - Mathew, Thomson K.: Study in the history of the pentecostal movement in South India, 1975
    Scope and Contents
    See Fiche B3500 0026
  - Roffey, John W.: Wisdom, law and blessing: an ethical hermeneutic of Deuteronomy and Matthew, [1981]
    See Fiche B3500 0038
  - Cleland, A. Craig: Center does not hold: a critical reading of Daniel 2 and 7, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0037
  - Damrow, William J.: Sex, marriage and family: a review and reappraisal of the Lutheran ethic for renewed dialogue, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0031
  - Finlayson, Marion: Korah's rebellion: a history of interpretation, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0024
  - Hoare, Geoffrey M. St. J.: Priesthood, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0036
  - Purpura, Joseph: Ministering to the bereaved: through an understanding of the Orthodox Christian Church's tradition, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0045
  - Streeter, Jarvis: Historical Jesus: a study of historical method and theology in Bultmann, Bornkamm, Jeremias, and Perrin, 1982
    See Fiche B3500 0035
  - Sonderegger, Katherine: Beyond the Father God: a feminist analysis, 1983
    See Fiche B3500 0041
  - Hwa, Chih: Examination into the translational problems of Job 13:28-14:22, 1984
    See Fiche B3500 0040
  - Donaldson, Audley St. Claire: Modern health care: its implications for the Caribbean church, 1985
    See Fiche B3500 0043
  - Isaacs, Wayne: Challenge of the poor in the Caribbean, 1985
    Fiche B3500 0013
  - Jenney, Ted J.: Concept of subjectivity: a mode of examination and discovery with reference to Kierkegaard and Wittgenstein, 1985
    See Fiche B3500 0013
  - Rose, Vernon J.: Doctrine of reconciliation: a Black South African perspective, 1985
    See Fiche B3500 0044
  - Zazzera, James G.: Easter vigil as liberating feast, 1985
    See Fiche B3500 0039
  - Hall, Mary H.: Subjective thinker: essays toward an oblique investigation of a concept with reference to its coinage by Soren Kierkegaard, 1986
    See Fiche B3500 0032
  - Holmes, Paul A.: Betrothal: a liturgical rite of passage, 1986
    See Fiche B3500 0012
  - Roth, Larry A.: Count Nicolaus Ludwig von Zinzendorf's theory for missions portrayed at Herrnhut and by selected 18th-20th century Moravian missions, 1986
    See Fiche B3500 0046
  - Adam, A. K. M.: Giving Jonah the fish-eye, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0010
  - Choy, Enoch: Theology of the heart: Choan-Seng Song's approach to theology and the Asian context, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0022
  - Cox, R. David: Vision to fulfill: "mutual responsibility and interdependence" in the Anglican communion, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0025
  - Dawson, David: Presbyterian missionaries in the Middle East, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0028
  - Dodge, Anne Elizabeth: Historical and analytical overview of North American Protestant missions in Zimbabwe, 1890-1987
    See Fiche B3500 0042
  - Henson, Michael A.: Nature and purpose of the church and its ministry: towards a new paradigm, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0005
  - Keller Bonsey, Steven C.: "When the soul unto the line accords": a proposal for the creative presentation of the gradual Psalm, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0029
  - Moore, David Lewis: Metropolitan African Methodist Episcopal Zion church: the remnant, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0027
  - O'Brien, James Randall: Analysis of parental influence upon conceptualization of and relationship to God, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0008
  - Sandau, Wayne Reinhold: Open church: diversity in the local congregation, 1987
    See Fiche B3500 0009
  - Erickson, S. Eric: Theological anthropology of Gregory of Nyssa: the role of the akolouthia in the De opificio hominis, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0011
  - Evans, Alexander W.: Theological reflection on ministry toward the 1990's, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0007
  - Gooch, Judith A.: Pastoral counseling: a ministry of the church, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0030
  - Hammond-Donkoh, Joseph: Akan mass: the impact of missionary activities on the traditional liturgies of the African church, 1988
    Fiche B3500 0004
  - Ip, King Tak: Emil Brunner's theology of marriage and family, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0016
  - Ireri, Gideon G.: Appropriating the message: the Anglican Mission (C.M.S.) in coastal and central Kenya 1844-1937, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0017
  - Lawler, Steven W. C.: Use of story in Christian religious education, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0015
  - Nembhard, Ralston B.: Radical obedience and discipleship in the theology of Dietrich Bonhoeffer, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0003
  - Oladipo, Caleb Oluremi, 1955-: Experience of the Holy Spirit in the indigenous African church, 1988
    See Fiche B3500 0033
  - Alford, Leslie M.: Towards a new spirituality in North America: the import of Dietrich Bonhoeffer's dialectical model of spirituality, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0060
  - Chan, Shun Lai: Reflection on the concept of the church in the Reformed tradition, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0021
  - Cho, Wai-tung: Theological anthropology of Paul Tillich, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0002
  - Cox, Christopher William: Approach to alcoholism for the clergy, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0023
  - Greene-McCreight, Kathryn, 1961-: Proposal of a Pauline paradigm for the relation of the church to the synagogue., 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0001
  - Greenwood, Richard H.: Stories for Theophilus: a collection of narrative sermons based on texts from the gospel according to St. Luke, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0048
  - Guerrero, Anacleto G.: Paul's Christological thought in his Letter to the Philippians, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0014
  - Hara, Masakazu: Critical realism in philosophy of science and its relevance to theology, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0034
  - Holmes, Jamie A. E.: Churches, leadership and transcendence, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0006
  - Kjelshus, Eddie Mark: Theology of ministry: the doctrine of vocation, 1989
    Fiche B3500 0019
  - Lipski, Victor: From false to true hopes: human hope, Christian hope and ethics, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0055
  - Null, Ashley: Rise of repentance: towards a recovery of Anglican identity, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0018
  - Ryou, Yunju: Understanding popular messianic belief around the time of Jesus and the messiahship of Jesus, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0058
  - Sween, Maurice Alwyn: Christian missions in the early church: historical considerations and contemporary reflections, 1989
    See Fiche B3500 0020
  - Anderson-Krengel, Wm. Erich.: Deaf ministry in the Episcopal Church, 1990
    See Fiche B3500 0049
  - Battle, Michael: Ethics of heaven: the concept of heaven in ethical thought, 1990
    See Fiche B3500 0050
  - Chang, Sok-chung: Exegetical study on 2 Kings 17: a historiographical approach to the Deuteronomistic history, 1990
    See Fiche B3500 0051
  - Chun, Soon-deug: Korean women in church and culture, 1990 (Box 40C)
  - Lara, James R.: Bipolar liturgical space in medieval Spain: the Coro Baio and Via Sacra, 1990